<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-03-12T23:52:30-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Mark’s Scratchpad</title><subtitle>Here I post research I'm doing, thoughts on technology or papers I'm reading  photography, and projects.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/07/10/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2018-07-10T22:58:33-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-10T22:58:33-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/07/10/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2018/07/10/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Repairing the Corsair 750 TX ATX Computer Power Supply</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/electronics/repair/2018/07/10/Corsair-TX750-ATX-PSU-Repair.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Repairing the Corsair 750 TX ATX Computer Power Supply" /><published>2018-07-10T22:58:33-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-10T22:58:33-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/electronics/repair/2018/07/10/Corsair-TX750-ATX-PSU-Repair</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/electronics/repair/2018/07/10/Corsair-TX750-ATX-PSU-Repair.html">&lt;p&gt;I built my first desktop somwhere between middle and high school, after struggling though games like Half-Life 2, Portal, and Team Fortress 2 on an old Dell Dimension 4770. If I remember correctly, that old machine barely supported PCIe GPUs; the other desktop I had managed to salvage from my school’s tech waste required AGP cards and was not much older. The ‘aftermarket’ GPU I added to the system was an &lt;em&gt;ATI&lt;/em&gt; Radeon 4670, and in spite of it’s own limitations was likely bottenecked by the Pentium 4 CPU and 2.5 GB of ram. To say nothing of the spinning rust that was my non-volatile storage medium…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, when I built my first rig aroumd 2010 or so, it was a massive improvement. A quad-core (unlocked, thanks AMD!) Phenom II 955 &lt;em&gt;Black Edition&lt;/em&gt; with a whole 4GB of ram, and an AMD 5770 GPU to top things off! The PSU was upgraded of course, the very same of which is the star of this blog post…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;INSERT IMAGE OF PSU HERE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Corsair TX 750 watt PSU served the power needs for my main desktop for over 5 years, well past the end of the official warrantly offered by Corsair. Considering that in the last two of those years I was routinely using my AMD FX 8350 CPU as a room heater in my upsate New York apartment during cold winters, it did a pretty good job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, though, the PSU started to show signs of trouble: the odd shutdown here, needing to power cycles two or three times to have the system POST, and finally, in the words of AvE, complete failure to chooch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;finding-the-fault&quot;&gt;Finding the Fault&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In spite of having taken a few courses by this point in the Electrical Engineering program at my university, I have not previously debugged a power delivery circuit of this complexity before. So, off to the two best friends of alll engineers and trouble-shooters: Google and StackOverflow! Eventually, I figured out that I should check for shorted semiconductor components – this indicates a dead diode or mosfet. Checking the active power factor correction circuit (aPFC) yeilded a shorted capacitor, a dead MOSFET, and a dead diode. Aside from these components, I also had to replace the input fuse since the failed components had caused a short from the mains inputs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;working-and-brighter-than-ever&quot;&gt;Working and Brighter than Ever!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall this repair turned out to not be too difficult to troubleshoot and repair, minus having to wait for the replacement parts to arrive in the mail. I even noticed that the PSU’s cooling fan included a few slots for LEDs, which I happily soldered in! A year later, this PSU is still trucking along just fine, though I do not use it in my primary desktop since I never bothered to swap it back in. Instead it powers my home NAS. Definitely no raised eyebrows for powering an important data repository with a home-refurbished power supply… :D&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I built my first desktop somwhere between middle and high school, after struggling though games like Half-Life 2, Portal, and Team Fortress 2 on an old Dell Dimension 4770. If I remember correctly, that old machine barely supported PCIe GPUs; the other desktop I had managed to salvage from my school’s tech waste required AGP cards and was not much older. The ‘aftermarket’ GPU I added to the system was an ATI Radeon 4670, and in spite of it’s own limitations was likely bottenecked by the Pentium 4 CPU and 2.5 GB of ram. To say nothing of the spinning rust that was my non-volatile storage medium…</summary></entry></feed>